NYSUT President's Office Files. 6174/001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Presidents files: Subseries 2
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 28)
    June 14, 2000. Agenda; draft Executive Committee Format, assuming all members have a fax and computer that will receive e-mail; privileged and confidential memo to NYSUT officers re limitation of representation in discipline, discharge and licensure proceedings (proposed revised policy re guaranteed representation in 3020a and Part 83 cases, as requested at Officers Retreat), December 3, 1999; letter to Hobart from Al Shanker's widow Eadie re archiving Shanker's records in collaboration with Cornell Kheel Center, May 30, 2000; letter of thanks for donation to AIDSWalk 2000; letters of thanks for COLA rally for retirees
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 29)
    May 30, 2000. Agenda; dues forecast; draft 2000-2001 budget, with cover memo explaining deficit, May 26; NYSUT equipment schedule; The Rochester Teacher newsletter, May 2000; letter from Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott, informing Hobart of nomination to Republican Senatorial Inner Circle, May 12; letter from Camden Teachers' Association re clothing drive under Local Action Pilot Program (LAPP), April 3; thank-you letters for support from National Committee on Pay Equity, Central NY Labor Agency, Regional Food Bank of Northeastern New York, others; letters from Assembly Speaker Sheldon Silver and U.S. Senator Chuck Schumer re speaking opportunity at Representative Assembly, gift of bookends; souvenir journal for Buffalo State College Foundation scholarship gala, "A Night in New York," April 8; memo from Elmsford Regional Office re lack of participation by school-related personnel (SRP) in NYSUT activities, summary of meeting with local leaders to discuss reasons, May 5; confidential memo discussing need for in-house attorney, May 12
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 30)
    April 14, 2000. Agenda; memo to Board of Directors from Tom Hobart, soliciting nominations for 1998-2000 committee appointments, June 2, 1998; materials from the National Alliance of Business, including 2000 Program Brief, brochures; letter to Hobart in care of VOTE/COPE from H. Carl McCall, thanking him for early support in gubernatorial race, March 14, 2000; memo re improving communication between board members by using e- mail; proposed AFT convention committee chair recommendations; list of other committee members
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 31)
    March 28, 2000. Agenda; memo summarizing survey of teachers, March 27; list of new hires, retirements, terminations, and promotions, "Personnel Activity," February 12-March 28; special order of business for Representative Assembly, "Solving the Teacher Shortage: A New 3 R's: Recruitment, Retention, and Retirements"; Business Plan for Gerontology Services, March 10; memo, A Summary of Federal Legislation to Repeal the Social Security Earnings Test, March 25; agenda for Representative Assembly 2000; letter to president of Lockheed-Martin from Assembly Majority Leader Michael Bragman, urging reversal of decision to lay off 21 janitorial workers, noting $8 million funding commitment by the State of New York, warning that future funding depended on reasonable and credible employment commitments by company, February 25; anti-labor letter from Senator Bob Smith, February 11; letter to AFT president Sandra Feldman from Nassau BOCES Central Council of Teachers, opposing full-year work schedule for teachers, with attached clipping from New York Times, discussing proposal by Secretary of Education, February 28
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 32)
    March 15, 2000. Agenda; Hart Research survey results of state and NYC public opinion on national candidates, education issues, February 28-March 2000; memo re underwriting PBS Inside Albany, March 14; business plan for proposed gerontology services program for NYSUT retiree members; thank-you letter from League of Women Voters Education Foundation for financial support, March 1; thank-you letter from NYS Public Employees Federation for $125,000 contribution for statewide advertising campaign, February 28; other thank-you letters and notes; letter from Orange-Ulster BOCES Paraprofessional Association, rescinding its letter of disaffiliation of October 21, 1999, January 20, 2000, with acknowledgement from NYSUT, January 26; letter from Amsterdam Teachers Association to Assembly member Paul Tonko, applauding his stance against charter schools, February 28, with attached newspaper clippings; letter to Hobart from Alternative Educational Enterprises, informing him of intention to explore creation of a charter school in Utica, March 5
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 33)
    February 23, 2000. Agenda; draft plan for UFT Campaign for New York Schools to increase public funding; preliminary proposal by M&R Strategic Services, "New York Campaign to Promote Public Education"; thank-you letters for financial support from Girl Scouts, Jewish Labor Committee, NYS Council of Senior Citizens, National Partnership for Women and Families, National Labor Committee in support of worker and human rights, Buffalo State College Foundation, others
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 34)
    February 1, 2000. Agenda; tentative agendas for Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings; agenda and minutes for Board of Trustees meeting for NYSUT Education and Learning Trust; content course development update for Effective Teaching Program, February 1; proposed resolution for Representative Assembly, opposing charter schools; memo from Commissioner of Education Richard Mills to Board of Regents re impending placement of schools under registration review (SURR), January 7; correspondence from local teacher associations; thank-you notes
  - Officers Meeting, 2000 (Box 93, Folder 35)
    January 6, 2000. Agenda; memo re organizing priorities and strategies, January 5; draft business items for Representative Assembly re career and technical education, educating students with disabilities in the least restrictive environment, expanding BOCES special education classroom space in school district buildings; draft resolution opposing charter schools; letter of thanks for financial support from Thoroughbred Retirement Foundation, with newsletter; letter of thanks for financial support from Rural Opportunities, Inc., with 30th anniversary yearbook; proposed guest list for 2000 Representative Assembly
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    December 14, 1999. Agenda; review of NYSUT print/mailing policy for locals; letter of thanks for financial support for tenth annual Celebrate Girls Luncheon from Girls Incorporated of the Greater Capital Region, October 18; souvenir journal for Albany District Chapter of the Links, Inc., "Cookin' with Jazz," October 17, with letter of thanks for support
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    December 7, 1999. Agendas for Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings; 2000 Proposed Constitutional Amendments; list of Charter Schools Institute applications; draft NYSUT expenditure authorization policy; confidential memo re Latham property acquisition, December 6
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    November 8, 1999. Agenda; privileged and confidential memo from office of general counsel re limitation of representation in discipline, discharge and licensure proceedings (3020a and Part 83), October 12; statement by AFL-CIO Executive Council, "Building a New Labor Movement in Our Communities: A New Alliance," August 3, 1999; related descriptions of New Alliance program; suggested activists list
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    October 25, 1999. Agenda; program for New York State AFL-CIO 15th Annual Labor Recognition Dinner: A Tribute to Edward J. Cleary, October 21, 1999; program for Board of Directors' retreat; discussion questions for sessions one and two; agenda for NYSUT Education and Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting of October 25; minutes of June 25 meeting
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    October 8, 1999. Agenda; souvenir program for New York State Capital Labor Parade, September 25; souvenir program for 1999 New York State Democratic Unity Reception
  - AFT, NEA, AFL-CIO Leadership Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    September 19-30, 1999. Agenda; testimony of NYSUT to the Board of Regents and the NYS Education Department at their Legislative Policy Conference, September 15, 1999; memo re purpose of meeting; booklet re NYSUT New Member Program
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    September 8, 1999. Agenda; agenda for Executive Committee meeting; memo re meeting with the Board of Regents re K-12, higher education, new standards, attacks on public schools, September 1; outline of VOTE/COPE goal setting, including mission statement, review of current structure, fundraising, disbursement of funds; tentative Representative Assembly program; proposal for board retreat; letter from NYS Department of Labor re needle stick injury prevention standards, August 25; letter from state senator Nick Spano, chair of Senate Labor Committee, sending Hobart greetings for Labor Day, noting support for organized labor and prevailing wage enforcement, pension protections, health insurance, other pro-labor issues, August 31; letters of thanks for financial support from Special Olympics New York, others
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    August 24, 1999. Agenda; photos of Hobart and NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese from Ellis Island event, May 8; memo from AFT president Sandra Feldman to Cortese, describing proposal by President Clinton for Medicare prescription drug plan, July 30; description of NYSUT's Local Union New Member Program; letter from League of Women Voters of New York State re "Students Inside Albany," four-day conference to increase awareness of citizen responsibility in representative government, June 1; results of evaluations of 1999 New Local Presidents' Conference; outline of discussion points of Leadership Training for Experienced Leaders; memo re increasing SRP (school-related personnel) participation in VOTE/COPE drives, July 23; letter to Hobart from the Cardinal's Committee of the Laity, thanking him for contribution of $3,000 to annual Construction and Building Industry Award Dinner, noting demand on Catholic Charities, July 21; 1999 report for the College Fund/UNCF (United Negro College Fund), with cover letter to Hobart, August 5; souvenir journal for 50th reunion of Brooklyn College (CUNY) Class of '49, with program and cover letter to Hobart from NYSUT Retired Educators' Chapter, Great Neck, June 4; New York Times clipping re Gov. Pataki's controversial appointment of former congressman and Bronx borough president Herman Badillo as chair of CUNY, May 31; NYT article on task force report on CUNY, June 8; Wall Street Journal article on charter schools in California, May 25; materials from the Epilepsy Foundation, NYS Labor-Religion Coalition, People for the American Way, Healing Fund (for victims of Columbine shooting), and others, thanking NYSUT for support; memo re meeting with NYS AFL-CIO president Denis Hughes, June 25; tentative agenda for June 24 meeting of Rochester Health Care Council; presentation re council; NYS AFL-CIO newsletter, Unity, with article re Zogby poll indicating wide support for raising minimum wage, May-June; document, Programs and Goals for 1984-85
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    June 1, 1999. Agenda; proposed 1999-2000 budget, June 1; souvenir program for Buffalo State College Foundation "A Night on the Nile" Scholarship Gala," April 17, 1999, with thank-you letter to Hobart for purchasing tickets; letter from Regent J. Edward Meyer to Assembly member Alexander J. Gromack, expressing concern over proposed legislation that would allow school districts to offer lower-standard alternatives to Regents Examinations such as the Regents Competency Tests or local diplomas; letter to Hobart from Coalition for Economic Justice, thanking him for NYSUT support for Sweatfree School Campaign, April 29; thank-you letters from New York African American Research Foundation, Hospice of Jefferson County, Judith Hope, state chair of the New York State Democratic Committee; materials from United Way re Healing Fund for survivors of Columbine school shooting, May; thank-you letter from First Lady Hillary Rodham Clinton for Steuben apple presented to her at convention, May 14; NYSUT New Staff Orientation Evaluation Forms (filled-in)
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    May 13, 1999. Agenda; NYSUT dues forecast; NYSUT Special Projects Budget 1999-2000; new position requests; revenue and expense sheets; proposal from Cornell University ILR School for NYSUT oral history project, December 7, 1998; thank-you notes from Special Olympics, American Red Cross of Northeastern New York, AFL-CIO Central Labor Council, and various NYSUT locals for support
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    May 4, 1999. Agenda; letter Cornell University ILR School re NYSUT oral history project proposal, December 7; 1998; letter from Thoroughbred Retirement Foundation re programs to rehabilitate and train incarcerated youth, April 8, 1999; newspaper clipping re teacher suspended with pay after admitting guilt in web porn case, "poster boy" for 3020-a reform; Student Association of the State of New York (SASU) 1999 Response to the Governor's Budget; program for Grassroots Legislative Conference & Student Lobby Day (co-sponsored by SASU and Prison Moratorium Project); newspaper clippings on NYS AFL-CIO coordinated day of action against proposed Pataki budget, with cover letter to Hobart from state president; letter from New York State Labor History Association, thanking NYSUT for contribution, with attached poster for Labor History month, April 16
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    April 14, 1999. Agenda; NYSUT Education & Learning Trust Board of Trustees agenda; list of 1999 Representative Assembly invited guests; racial and ethnic data for Education and Learning Trust teacher constituency, March 1; financial statements; memos and related materials re Rochester Association of Paraprofessionals separation from the Rochester Teachers Association, April 16; proposal for improving New York Teacher's reach to UFT readers; thank-you letters from various organizations and individuals
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    March 12-13, 1999. Evaluation forms re meeting format, with cover memo summarizing comments
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 14)
    March 9, 1999. Agenda; summary of February 3 VOTE/COPE meeting; memo re proposed conditions on free airline tickets given to NYSUT officers upon retirement, February 22; thank-you note to Hobart for contribution to Schodack Central School Faculty Association to compensate teachers for losses from asbestos contamination of elementary school, February 4; letter to Hobart from Cornell ILR professor Samuel Bacharach asking for support for school's new Masters in Professional Studies (MPS) degree program and Institute for Workplace Studies, February 26; draft 1999 Special Order of Business, NYSUT Response to the Proposed Regulations of the Commissioner Regarding Teacher Certification; data re NYSUT expenditures for overtime, part-time, interns, and law clerks for 1996, 1997, and 1998; request for approval for secretarial position
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 15)
    February 23, 1999. Agenda; letter to Hobart from Representative Amo Houghton (R), expressing thanks for note re (President Bill Clinton) impeachment inquiry, calling it "a mess," asserting it was "destroying my party," February 3, 1999; newspaper clipping re possible run for U.S. Senate from New York by First Lady Hillary Clinton; letter from Schalmont Teachers Association to Scotia-Glenville Teachers Association, re dispute over NYSUT redistricting, February 12; thank-you letters from American Red Cross of Northeastern New York, American Heart Association, Jewish Labor Committee, and others
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 16)
    February 1, 1999. Agenda; memo re changes in NYSUT reimbursement policy; Draft Report for Task Force on Minority Involvement in NYSUT; proposed resolutions by the Board of Directors to the 1999 Representative Assembly; proposal for NYSUT oral history project, from Cornell ILR School, December 7, 1998; memo re proposed memorial sculpture honoring Al Shanker, a replica of which would be awarded to recipients of the Shanker Distinguished Service Award, with attached illustrations and photos, February 1; proposed 1999 Representative Assembly guest list; proposed statement by Public Private School Forum, to be discussed at special meeting of AFT Executive Committee, "National Public, Private and Religious Organizations United in Support of Title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act," with cover letter from AFT president Sandra Feldman, January 11; fall 1998 issue of Thursday's Child, publication of United States Commission for UNICEF; thank-you letters from Italian-American Labor Council and others
  - Officers Meeting, 1999 (Box 94, Folder 17)
    January 5, 1999. Agenda; list of responses from members recruited to chair Representative Assembly committees
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 18)
    December 15, 1998. Agenda; position request and job description for assistant to the president; materials for Nontraditional Employment for Women (NEW), including letter from President Bill Clinton; materials for AIDS Walk '98 for the Capital Region
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 19)
    December 15, 1998. Agenda; agenda of NYSUT Education & Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting of December 1, 1998; minutes of June 24 and October 8, 1998, meetings; letter of support from Hobart to Jersey City Education Association's efforts to gain a fair contract, November 25; photo of Hobart at AFT State Federation Presidents' Award Luncheon, with letter, December 1
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 20)
    November 17, 1998. Agenda; Administrative Committee agenda; memo re pension supplementation for NYSUT retirees; memo re technology infrastructure upgrades and budget requests; correspondence re AFT Lessons for Life campaign; memo re retirement calculations for potential retirees; memos re underwriting for public broadcasting stations, November 13; draft final report of NYSUT Capital Area ED Redistricting Committee; memo re media coverage on raising teachers' standards; souvenir journal, Annual Awards Celebration, New York Committee on Occupational Safety & Health, November 12, 1998; souvenir journal for 62nd New York State Conference of NAACP Branches, October 9-11, 1998; thank-you notes
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 21)
    November 2, 1998. Agenda; 1998 souvenir journal for Jewish Labor Committee; Field and Legal Report, November 2; newspaper clippings; NYSUT Policy Manual summary; letters of interest by potential Unity Caucus appointments to at-large seats on NYSUT board; materials from the Oneida County School and Business Alliance (SABA); Business Council of New York State comments on "Essential Elements of Reading" document, October 30; draft NYSUT Policy for Professional Development and the Annual Professional Performance Review; draft recommendations of Safety Net Study Group for possible NYSUT policy in response to proposed changes in the Part 100 [Commissioners'] Regulations
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 22)
    October 20, 1998. Agenda; Representative Assembly site comparisons, 1999-2003; cumulative statistical report from 1978 through 1998; correspondence from locals
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 23)
    October 8, 1998. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Education & Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting; Effective Teaching Program workshops, September 1 - October 30, 1988; agreement between the Education and Learning Trust of New York State United Teachers and Adelphi University, September 23, 1998; agreement with Long Island University; memo re CUNY sponsorship of ETP courses; tentative audit schedule; list of accomplishments of Effective Teaching Program, 1997-98; Labor's Heritage, quarterly journal of George Meany Memorial Archives, vol. 9, no. 3; program for Joe Glazer 80th Birthday Tribute; press release from Department of the Treasury, "Secretary Rubin Announces $75 Million in CDFI Fund Awards," September 28; United Negro College Fund 1998 Annual Report; program for Buffalo State College Foundation Scholarship Golf Classic, September 14; minutes of Commit to Kids Steering Committee meeting, September 1; thank-you notes from community organizations, locals, and individuals for financial support; newsletter, The Rochester Teacher; newsletter of United Staff Association of NYU, The 3882 Local News, July/August; invitation to Bell Zeller Scholarship Trust Fund Friends of CUNY Award event; Presidents History Report (spreadsheet re local presidents), 1972-99; recommended members of Task Force on Minority Involvement in NYSUT Locals; letters to individual inviting her to serve on task force; memo recommending reimbursement amount for Carol Slotkin legal expenses, October 8
  - Officers Meeting, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 24)
    September 9, 1998. Agenda; Executive Committee meeting tentative agenda for September 17; Board of Directors' meeting tentative agenda for September 17; master list of potential NYSUT headquarters sites; proposed NYSUT committees, 1998-2000; materials for 1999 NYSUT Leadership Institute at Cornell; tentative program, rules of order, deadlines for 1999 Representative Assembly; letter to Hobart from Mort Bahr, president of Communication Workers of America, noting that he shared Hobart's concern re Working Families Party, and that he'd been assured that it would not become a political party "in the truest sense," July 16, with attached newspaper clipping, "Working Families Party has potential for future political impact in New York"; related clipping, "Coalition of union leaders pushes to create new party"; thank-you notes from individuals and organizations, including Amnesty International American Red Cross in Greater New York; International Rescue Committee Report, with cover letters; letter from Member of Congress Jack Quinn re effort to defeat "fast track" trade authority to president, hold hearings on constitutionality of NAFTA, July 31
  - Administrative Committee, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    June 1, 1999. Agenda; report, "NEA Relations: Proposed Guidelines for Mergers of American Federation of Teachers and National Education Association State Affiliates"; summary report for NYSUT tax-sheltered savings and investment plans as of April 30, 1999; materials for third annual NYSUT /Cornell ILR Leadership Institute; document, Assignment of RA Resolutions and Special Orders of Business, June 1, 1999
  - Administrative Committee, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    May 14, 1999. Agenda; status report on web site training for locals
  - Administrative Committee, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    May 4, 1999. Agenda; tentative schedule and related information for AFT conference, "Building Better Schools: It's Union Work: QuEST '99"; NYSUT booklet, "Programs, Services, Publications," revised July 1997; 1999 Representative Assembly Report on Attendance; Resolution 32, Health Insurance Protection for Retirees
  - Administrative Committee, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    April 14, 1999. Agenda; report, "Implementation of Actions by the 1998 Representative Assembly"; agenda for Local Presidents Conference and 1999 Representative Assembly programs
  - Administrative Committee, 1999 (Box 95, Folder 5)